class MAPEH {
  static const List<Map<String, dynamic>> thirdPeriodical =
      <Map<String, dynamic>>[
    {
      'answer': 'Mindoro',
      'question': 'is the seventh largest island in the country.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Tagalog',
      'question': 'inhabited in the plains of Occidental Mindoro.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Mangyans',
      'question':
          'inhabited in the remote forested interior of Occidental Mindoro.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Music',
      'question':
          "is an important part of Occidental Mindoro's everyday activities.",
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Ambahan',
      'question': 'a poem with lines consisting of seven syllables.',
    },
    {'answer': 'Ambahan', 'question': 'It is used for courting.'},
    {'answer': 'Iyaya', 'question': 'lullabies song.'},
    {'answer': 'Igway', 'question': 'vocal music.'},
    {'answer': 'Marayaw', 'question': 'spirit song.'},
    {'answer': 'Ngayung', 'question': 'ritual chants.'},
    {
      'answer': 'Urukay',
      'question':
          'a song often performed during courtship or to bring cheer to other occasions such as feasts and litigation meetings.',
    },
    {'answer': 'Urukay', 'question': 'it uses eight syllables'},
    {'answer': 'Pamuybuyen', 'question': 'a song about legends.'},
    {
      'answer': 'Mangyans',
      'question': 'the indigenous group who reside in Mindoro',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'craft',
      'question':
          'has always been a part of their way of life and an extension of their customs and traditions.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'ramit',
      'question': 'a textile made by the Buhid and Hanunuo Mangyans.',
    },
    {'answer': 'harablon', 'question': 'a woven on a backstrap loom'},
    {
      'answer': 'Marinduque',
      'question':
          "is referred to as the 'Heart of the Philippines' and the home of the Moriones Festival.",
    },
    {'answer': 'buri', 'question': 'raffia plants'},
    {
      'answer': 'Mat weaving',
      'question': 'is popular in Marinduque and represents their way of life.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Moriones Festival',
      'question': 'is an annual festival held during Holy Week',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'morion masks',
      'question':
          'participants wear these masks to imitate the Roman soldiers in a reenactment of the Passion of',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Moriones costumes',
      'question':
          'are made of capiz shells, hard wood, metal, and cloth that are sewn, carved, and stitched together.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Romblon',
      'question':
          'is known as the marble country because of its bountiful marble products such as jars, mortars and pestles, ashtrays, and souvenirs.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Dual sport',
      'question':
          'is a sport you play either singles or doubles against someone else.',
    },
    {'answer': 'doubles', 'question': 'a team consists of two people.'},
    {
      'answer': 'Calcium',
      'question':
          'for the development, growth, and maintenance of bone tissues.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Protein',
      'question':
          'this avoids gastrointestinal disorders, chronic infections, and injury.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Iron',
      'question': 'is required for the synthesis of hemoglobin.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'hemoglobin',
      'question':
          "the pigment in the red blood cells that carries oxygen from the lungs to the body's tissues and returns carbon dioxide from the tissues back to the lungs.",
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Phosphorous',
      'question': 'this filters waste and repairs tissues and cells.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Sodium',
      'question': 'It is only needed in small quantities in natural foods.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Sodium deficiency',
      'question': 'occurs because of low salt intake.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'diuresis',
      'question': 'failure to rid the body of excess fluid.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Iodine',
      'question':
          'is necessary for the synthesis of the hormones in the thyroid gland.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Vitamins',
      'question':
          'These are organic compounds that the body is unable to synthesize and must be supplied in the diet.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Nutritional guidelines',
      'question':
          'are simple rules or recommendations on practical nutrition that will motivate people to enjoy and combine a sufficient and well-balanced diet together with a healthy lifestyle.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Micronutrient deficiencies',
      'question':
          'can be corrected through the consumption of more vegetables and root crops.',
    },
    {
      'answer': 'Root crops',
      'question': 'can supplement dietary energy to any food intake.',
    },
  ];
  static const List<Map<String, dynamic>> thirdMonthly = <Map<String, dynamic>>[
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Indigenous tradition',
      'question':
          'is practiced by some groups of people who live in the mountains of northern Luzon.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Salidomay',
      'question':
          'a familiar folk song especially from the people of Ifugao, Bonto Province.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Hudhud ni Aliguyon',
      'question':
          'an epic song performed through chanting with women as the lead singers.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Dong-dong-ay si Dong-ilay',
      'question':
          'a traditional tune popularized by the guerrilla soldiers during World War II.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Cavite',
      'question':
          'is known for its rich history and large number of national heroes.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Land of the Brave',
      'question': 'Cavite is known as this.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Fishing',
      'question': 'is one of their primary sources of livelihood in Cavite.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Tinis',
      'question':
          'Cavite is also known for this in Kawit which is celebrated during the Christmas season.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Tinis',
      'question':
          'is a festival that narrates the story of how Joseph and Mary found a place to give birth to Jesus.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Laguna',
      'question': 'is the hometown of our national hero, Dr. Jose P. Rizal.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Paete, Laguna',
      'question': 'Famous woodcrafts are done here.',
    },
    <String, String>{'answer': 'ukit', 'question': 'hook carvings.'},
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Taka',
      'question':
          'is a papier-mache technique which has become the epitome of Filipino folk art.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Kayas',
      'question':
          'is a type of art made by scraping softwood into beautiful floral and faunal decorations.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Batangas',
      'question':
          'is famous for its embroidered pinya fabric made from pineapple fiber.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Taal',
      'question':
          'is known as the barong tagalog and balisong capital of the Philippines.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Rizal',
      'question': "they called it 'the arts town region' in the Philippines.",
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Angono, Rizal',
      'question': 'is famous for its Higantes Festival.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': '23rd of November',
      'question': 'Higantes Festival celebration date.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Perdigon Vocalan',
      'question': 'he conceptualized Higantes in 1980.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'pahadores',
      'question':
          "devotees dress in colorful local costumes of fishermen's clothes.",
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'higantes',
      'question':
          'papier-mache giants measuring 10-12 feet in height and 4-5 feet in diameter.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Quezon province',
      'question': 'was named after Manuel L. Quezon.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Manuel L. Quezon',
      'question': 'the 2nd President of the Philippines.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Pahiyas Festival',
      'question': 'is a thanksgiving festival for a bountiful harvest.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'kiping',
      'question': 'colorful decors made from ground.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'glutinous rice',
      'question': 'are thinly coated on special leaves.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Bicol Region',
      'question': 'is the largest island in the Philippines.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Ilocos',
      'question': 'Vigan houses are found in?',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Vigan',
      'question': 'It is considered as the Intramuros of the North.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'abel',
      'question': 'In Ilocano, it refers to the process of weaving.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'abel',
      'question':
          'is the final woven product made from cotton and other natural fibers.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'binatbatan',
      'question':
          'It is a way of beating the cotton balls using bamboo sticks.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'burnay',
      'question': 'a kind of dark earthenware made in Vigan.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Tinis and Shell Handicrafts',
      'question': 'arts and crafts or significant events in Cavite.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Taka and Kayas',
      'question': 'arts and crafts or significant events in Laguna.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Barong Tagalog and Balisong',
      'question': 'arts and crafts or significant events in Batangas.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Higantes and Pahadores',
      'question': 'arts and crafts or significant events in Rizal.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Kiping and Pahiyas Festival',
      'question': 'arts and crafts or significant events in Quezon.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'Slippers and Tampipi',
      'question': 'arts and crafts or significant events in Bicol.',
    }
  ];
}
